時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
여행 도중 무사시 일행은 바이켄과 재회했다.
During their trip, Musashi and others met with Baiken once again.
그리고 바이켄은 훌륭한 저택에서 요리를 대접해 주었다.
And Baiken gave them a dish in a superb residence.
그러나 기쁨도 잠시, 괴물 누에하고 싸우는 처지가 되었다.
But their happiness didn't last long; they had to fight against a monster named Nue.
하지만 바이켄의 우정의 조력과 코지로의 협력으로 오니히메가 조종하는 누에를 쓰러뜨리고 다테 가를 구했다.
But thanks to aid of the friendship with Baiken and cooperation of Kojirō,
they took Nue under the control of Onihime down and saved Date family.
슈텐, 대폭발이오
Shuten Explodes
이 깊숙한 곳의 저주의 골짜기. 대체 뭔 일인가.
The Cursed Valley is over deep there. What is going on?
뭔가, 저건...
What could that be?
게다가 행방불명된 고하치도 헤이스케도 있군.
Missing Gohachi and Heisuke are also there!
마을 사람들에게 알려야...
I must let villagers know about this.
역시 길을 잘못 든 게.
Are you sure that we aren't lost?
내 코에 문제는 없소!
My nose do not have a problem-dasu!
과학적 근거는 제로구나.
You have zero scientific evidences.
그런 것 아니오.
That's not it-dasu.
둘 다 쓸데없는 걸로 싸우지 마! 빨리 번화가에 있는 역참이나 가자.
Don't fight with something that pointless! Let's just hurry up to an inn in a lively town.
여기서는 어떻게 해도 못 찾을 거야.
We're not going to find one in this rate.
어?
Huh?
이거! 내 코는 역시 잘 듣소! 맛있어 보이는 만두이오!
This! My nose definitely works perfectly-dasu! Tasty-looking dumplings-dasu!
어이! 무사시!
Hey, Musashi!
무사시!
Musashi!
누구냐?!
Who is it?!
카라쿠리 무예가! 나하고 승부다!
Karakuri martial artist! Have a match with me!
승부?
A match?
관둬라, 얘야.
Forget it, kiddo.
얘 아니야! 나, 산타야! 승부해!
I am not a kiddo! I am Santa! Face me!
이런 비겁한 놈! 얘라고 해도 용서 못 하오!
You coward! I won't forgive even a child-dasu!
지장보살의 공물에 손을 댔기 때문이다!
It's because you touched the offering to Ksitigarbha!
뭐, 뭣이오?!
W- what?!
거기까지, 무사시.
Stop right there, Musashi.
산타가 말하는 대로! 천한 짓을 하니까 그러지!
Just as Santa said! It's all because you were being crude!
그래도 코지로가 용돈도 안 주고 밥도 안 사 주니까...
But Kojirō don't give me any allowance or buy me a food...
어째서 떠돌고 있나.
Why are you wandring?
조금 실력을 시험해 봤어.
I just tested my skills.
시험?
Test?
알겠어! 너도 무예가가 되고 싶은 거구나?
I see! You want to be a martial artist, right?
난 당연히 아빠같은 부모님이 될 거야!
I will become a parent like my dad!
사정이 있는 것 같구나.
It seems that you have some situation.
폼내는 것 같긴 해도 조금은 할 줄 아는 것 같네. 널 고용할게.
While you look like you're showing off, you seem to be with some skills. I'll hire you.
날 고용해?
Hire me?
물론 공짜는 아니고, 내 보물이야.
It's not for free, of course. Take my treasure.
이건 사금!
This is alluvial gold!
그러니까 금이오?
Is that gold in other words-dasu?
어라, 꽤 굵구나.
Those are large drops!
받아 줄거야?
Will you accept this?
음, 그래도...
But, you know...
내가 받아 주겠소!
I will take that instead-dasu!
너라면 아빠 못 구해!
You are not skilled enough to save my dad!
칫, 귀엽지 않소...
Tch, he's not cute at all...
-코지로?
-가만히 두고만 볼 수는 없네요.
-Kojirō?
-I can't just let this pass by.
저만큼의 금이 있다면, 만두에 단고에 양갱에...
With gold that much, I'll be able to get dumplings, dangos, sweet red bean paste, ...
배가 가득히 차도록 먹겠소!
I'll finally be able to fill my stomach to the full extent-dasu!
아, 기다리시오! 나도 가오!
Hey, wait for me! I'm going too-dasu!
지라이얀, 뭐냐.
What is it, Jiraiyan?
슈텐에게서, 빛을 갚고 싶다고...
Shuten wanted to pay back his debts with me.
금괴인가... 그러나 이 정도만 올려봤자 센히메 습격 실패의 속죄는 되지 않는다.
Gold bars, eh... But this is not enough for redemption of failure of assaulting Senhime.
잘 알고 있습니다. 이것보다도 몇만, 몇백 만 양의 군자금을 대신 바치고 싶다고...
We know that well. Not only this, but also we wanted to offer you war funds of thousands and millions of ryos instead.
그렇다면 이야기가 다르다. 제너럴 이에야스를 쓰러뜨리고 쇼군이 되기 위한 막대한 군자금가 있으니 말이지.
Now that's an another story. There are lot of war funds required to take General Ieyasu down and become Shōgun.
예. 슈텐과 함께 군자금을 만들어 오겠습니다.
Yessir. I'll be back after making war funds with Shuten.
그럼.
Then.
기다려라, 지라이얀.
Wait, Jiraiyan.
금산은 슈텐에게 맡겨라. 너는 주베를 쫓아라.
Leave the gold mountain to Shuten. You will keep an eye on Jūbee.
주베를?
Jūbee?
주베 놈...
That Jūbee bastard...
센히메 일행을 그림자 속에서 지키며 뒤에서 우리 행동을 감시하고 있는 게 명백하다.
It is clear that he is protecting Senhime and others in shadow and observing us in the back.
그러니까, 지라이얀, 너는 주베의 행방을 밝혀내어 암살해라.
That's why I'm ordering you, Jiraiyan, to find out Jūbee's traces and assassinate him.
예.
Yessir.
그리고 센히메를 억누를 때, 단숨에 막부를 쓰러뜨리겠다.
And when we got Senhime in our hands, we'll take the shōgunate down at once.
그 이후에는 이 한조의 천하가 되는 것이다.
And then, the world will fall into my hands.
행방불명?
Missing?
응, 사냥하러 간 사람이나 버섯 따러 간 사람이라던가... 우리 마을에도 8명이야.
Yeah. People who went to hunt or to mushroom... There are 8 people from our village.
그리고 아버지도...
And your dad, too...
이 저주의 골짜기에 마물이 있는 게 틀림없어.
In The Cursed Valley, there must be an evil creature.
응.
Yeah.
음? 내 코가 무언가를 느끼오.
Hm? My nose is detecting something-dasu.
물고기가 죽어 있소.
That fish is dead-dasu.
어떻게 된 일이오?
What's going on-dasu?
분명 이 물은 독일 거야.
The water must be toxic.
역시 마물이 자리잡은 거야.
A evil creature must have took his place.
뭐가 마물이오! 이 무사시가 이도류로 팍팍 썰어 주겠소!
There's nothing to worry about that evil creature-dasu! I'll cut it with my dual blades-dasu!
그리고...
And...
마물의 소리야.
It's the sound of that creature.
저것이 마물의 소리이오.
That's the sound of the creature.
내게 맡기시오!
Leave it to me-dasu!
저건 센히메와 무사시 일행.
There are Senhime and Musashi.
오, 오로치!
O- Orochi!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
그 때의 실패, 녀석들에게 받은 굴욕은 죽어도 잊지 않겠다.
I will never forget the failure and the humiliation I received from them even if I die.
저주의 골목이 너희들의 영원한 무덤이 될 지어다.
The Cursed Valley will be your permanent graves.
두고 보자.
You will see.
이, 이건...
T- this is...
아빠!
Daddy!
산타, 오지 마라!
Do not come, Santa!
아빠!
Daddy!
산타!
Santa!
네 이놈, 괴물 놈!
You monster bastard!
했겠소!
You really did it!
으악! 몸이 뻣뻣해지오!
My body is getting stiff-dasu!
산타!
Santa!
아빠!
Daddy!
무사시! 산타!
Musashi! Santa!
센히메 님, 숨어 계세요.
Senhime, please hide in somewhere safe.
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
괜찮나?
Are you alright?
네 이놈!
You bastard!
코지로!
Kojirō!
너는...
You...!
이하 사천왕의 하나. 슈텐타이거!
One of Four Iga Kings, Shutentiger!
오늘로써 원한을 풀어 주겠다!
I will resolve my hatred as of today!
코지로에 무사시, 천천히 요리해 주겠다.
Kojirō and Musashi, I will cook you slowly.
아빠뿐만이 아니라 모두 다... 이걸 어째...
Not only my dad but also everyone... What should I do?
자, 절체절명의 대위기! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
What a big and severe crisis! Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
이 보물과 함께 공물로 함께 보내 주겠다. 그 때까지 얌전히 있어라.
I will send you as an offering along with these treasures. Behave until then.
무사시... 코지로...
Musashi... Kojirō...
이 놈들아! 똑바로 일해라!
You brats! Work properly!
이런 방해꾼이 되고 싶나?
Do you want to become like this hinderance?
빨랑빨랑 일해라!
Hurry up and work!
자, 저 녀석들을 어떻게 요리해 줄까.
Now, how should I cook them up?
아빠...
Dad...
산타...
Santa...
아, 아빠!
Hey, dad!
그렇구나. 진흙이니까 물에 약하지!
I see! Mud melts by water!
산타!
Santa!
아빠!
Dad!
한방에 모가지를 날리는 것으로는 원한이 안 풀리지.
Cutting your neck into two at once won't resolve my hatred.
이걸로 조금씩 조금씩 죽여 주겠어.
I will kill you with this, little by little.
어떠냐, 기분은?
How does that feel?!
그렇군, 그렇군! 기쁘구나!
I see, I see! You're happy!
그만두시오!
Stop it-dasu!
이제 곧이다, 무사시! 슬슬 체인소가 네 몸을 찢어갈길 거야.
It's almost there, Musashi! My chainsaw will tear off your body into pieces.
오, 닿은 것 같구나. 지금 두 동강내 주겠다.
It seems that it's touching your body. Time to break you into two pieces.
이랴!
Take this!
너희들! 뭔 짓이냐!
You guys! What was that for?!
이랴!
Take this!
용서할 수 없다!
Unforgivable!
산타!
Santa!
죽어라!
Die!
스톱이오!
Stop-dasu!
내가 상대해 주겠소!
I'll face you-dasu!
건방진 꼬맹이군! 원하는 대로 상대해 주겠다!
What an impudent brat! I'll face you as you wished!
산타, 코지로하고 오센짱을 부탁하오!
Santa, please take care of Kojirō of Osenchan-dasu!
맡겨 둬!
Leave it to me!
그래도 다시 봤어, 무사시!
Anyway, I'm looking you again, Musashi!
에이, 주제넘게 이도류 따위를 쓰다니!
How audacious of you, to use dual blades?!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, 등장해라!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, rise up!
또 나왔소! 아까 그 괴물!
You're here again-dasu! That monster before!
저런, 그 수는 다시는 안 먹히오!
Oh, that's not gonna work anymore-dasu!
교활하오!
That's cheating-dasu!
또 꼴불견이오!
I look miserable again-dasu!
눈이 팽팽 도오~
My eyes are spinning-dasu~
적당히 좀 하시오!
Cut it off-dasu!
무사시! 그 흙인형 진흙으로 되어 있어!
Musashi! That clay warrior is made out of mud!
진흙은 물에 약해!
Water will melt mud!
알았소!
I got it-dasu!
여기까지 쫒차 보시오, 진흙더미! 어떤지!
Chase me if you can, you pile of mud-dasu! How's this?!
해냈소!
I did it-dasu!
슈텐! 츠바메가에시를 받아보아라!
Shuten! Take my Tsubamegaeshi!
아무리 비검 츠바메가에시라 해도, 두번은 안 통한다!
Secret sword or not, that Tsubamegaeshi won't work twice!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, 바위 으깨기!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, rock smasher!
잘도 했겠소!
You really did it-dasu!
그런 요술, 비겁하오! 검으로 사내답게 승부보시오!
Using magic is cowardly-dasu! Face me with your sword like a real man-dasu!
웃기지 마라! 이기면 된다. 이기면.
Don't make me laugh! Winning is important. Winning.
누, 누구냐?
W- who was that?!
에잇, 이 꼬맹이!
That brat!
지금이오!
Now's the time-dasu!
뭐야?!
What?!
칼이 빠지지 않아!
I can't take my sword back!
이천일류, 가위치기의 칼이오!
Niten'ichiryū - Sword of Crab's Scissors!
위험했다.
That was close.
또 멋진 척하기는. 혼자서라도 충분히 되오!
Acting cool again? I'm more than enough for that-dasu!
나도 한 번은 잘난 꼴 보여줘야지.
I gotta show off for at least once.
네이놈! a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, 허리케인 정태!
You bastard! a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, hurricane state!
자, 코지로 씨하고 무사시 씨를 구해라!
We'll rescue Mr. Kojirō and Mr. Musashi!
이랴!
Push!
-회오리가
-멈췄어!
-The tornado
-has stopped!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
슈텐, 각오!
Prepare yourself, Shuten!
이천일류, 십자 가르기!
Niten'ichiryū, Ten(十) Shaped Cut!
와, 예쁘다!
Wow, it's pretty!
이야...
Whoa...
으악, 금이오, 금이오! 더는 팔 수 없소!
Ack, it's gold-dasu, it's gold-dasu! I can't collect them in this rate-dasu!
네 이놈... 또 무사시 일행이 방해를...
Those bastards... Musashi's group is interfering again...
용서할 수 없다! 어떤 수를 써서라도 반드시 목숨을 끊어 주겠다.
Unforgivable! I will employ any means to take their lives away!
정말 어떤 보답을 해야 할지...
We are sincerely grateful for all your work here.
고마워. 코지로 씨. 오센짱.
Thank you, Mr. Kojirō and Osenchan.
으응, 아버지도 이제 산타의 기분을 알아주셨을 거야.
Your dad surely have understood your feelings by now, Santa!
-어라, 무사시는?
-어?
-Hey, where's Musashi?
-Huh?
저 만큼의 금이 팍 흩어졌소.
All that gold were spread into air-dasu.
그런대로 밥이라도 먹어서 본전을 찾겠소.
I'm going to recover my investment by eating rice-dasu.
어이, 무사시! 게걸스러운 짓 하지 마라!
Hey, Musashi! Don't be voracious!
으악, 한 입만 더...
One more bite...
정말 먹보라니까.
He's such a glutton.
맞는 말입니다. 수행하는 주제에, 게다가 큰 목적이 있는 여행인데도.
You're right. He should be practicing self-discipline, and moreover, this is a trip with an importan objective.
배고프오... 단고... 만두...
I'm hungry... Dango... Dumpling...
-무사시 씨!
-어?
-Mr. Musashi!
-Huh?
산타!
Santa!
뭔 일 있소?
What's wrong-dasu?
이거! 도시락이야.
Here! Your lunch box.
우와! 역시 산타네 부모님이오!
Yes! Santa's parents are great!
배가 고프면 수행할 수 없잖아. 똑바로 해, 무사시!
You can't train when you're hungry. Do it properly, Musashi!
알겠소! 힘내겠소!
Got it! I'll do my best-dasu!
어라, 이 녀석, 지팡구 제일의 내게 건방지오!
Hey, are you being cocky to me, the number one of Jipangu?
이랴!
I'll get you!
도울 생각이 도움으로, 창피를 당해도 사랑을 위해, 거센 콧김도 타개해 가는 것이 남자의 삶의 태도이다.
Thinking to help and actually helping, for the love despite any humiliation during the help,
a man must have a way of life of breaking through the violent wind of flowers.
들에 피는 꽃이 웃을 때구나. 가라, 가라, 무사시! 힘껏 부딪혀라!
Wild flowers are smiling. Go, go, Musashi! Hit hard!
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
여행의 노고를 푸는 데에는 온천이 제일! 그래서 무심히 외딴 곳의 온천장 여관에 멈추었지만,
Hot springs are the best when we're tired from a journey! That's why we stopped by a hot spring hotel-dasu,
이 무슨! 이 주변엔 죽은 사람의 영혼이 모이는 산이 있다니.
but what?! There's a mountain around here which dead people's spirits gather.
나, 거기서 그리운 이시마츠 씨하고 재회했소! 와, 방황하지 말고 성불하길 바라오!
I met again with my beloved Mr. Ishimatsu there-dasu! I wish him to go to heaven without getting lost!
다음 이야기! 히익! 이시마츠의 유령이오
Next story! Woah! It's Ishimatsu's Ghost!
질풍노도의 대영계이오!
It's a stormy great spiritual realm-dasu!
다음 이야기
히익! 이시마츠의 유령이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Woah!
It's Ishimatsu's Ghost!
Look forwards for it!